Guide to the Shepherd Stevens Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Lecture and class material, 1896-1947; Series VI
  - Student work
    - Lecture notebooks
      - Columbia University
        - 1901 October-1902 May (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Cornell University
        - 1915 October-November (Box 39, Folder 14)
        - 1915 December-1916 May (Box 39, Folder 15)
        - 1916 May-1920 June (Box 39, Folder 16)
      - École des Beaux-Arts
        - 1904-1905 (Box 40, Folder 1)
        - 1906-1907 (Box 40, Folder 2-4)
        - Circa 1905-circa 1907 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Professional work
    The Professional work contains Stevens's teaching materials from Yale University, which have been kept in the original order.
    - Teaching materials - Yale University
      - "Greek Architecture", 1937, 1941, undated (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
      - "Roman Architecture", 1941, undated (Box 41, Folder 3-4)
      - "History of Architecture-Egypt-Mesopotamia", 1929, 1945, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - "Mediaeval History-Indian Architecture", Undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - "Rayonnant Architecture", 1932, 1946, undated (Box 41, Folder 7-8)
      - "French Romanesque Architecture", Undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - "German and Flemish Gothic Architecture", 1934, undated (Box 41, Folder 10)
      - "Spanish Gothic Architecture", 1938, 1945, undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - "Gothic Secular Architecture", 1942, undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - "Romanesque Architecture", 1942, undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - "Byzantine Architecture", 1936-1942, undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - "English Gothic Architecture", Undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - "Mediaeval Architecture-Carolingian", 1943, undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - "French Romanesque Architecture", 1928, 1938, undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - "Italian Gothic Architecture", 1928, 1931, undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - "Flamboyant Gothic Architecture", 1927-1928 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - "Italian Villas", 1931 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - "Early Christian Architecture", 1933-1935, 1941, undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - "Lombard Romanesque Architecture", 1927, 1933, undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - "Central and South Italian Romanesque Architecture", Undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - "Early Transitional Gothic Architecture", 1928, undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - "Gothic Architecture", 1930 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - "Italian Renaissance Architecture outside of Florence", 1930 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - "English Renaissance Architecture–Georgian and Adam", 1939, undated (Box 43, Folder 9)
      - "Early Italian Renaissance Architecture", Undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
      - "Interior Decoration", Undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
      - "English Renaissance Architecture to Georgian", 1930-1934, 1940-1942, undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
      - "Spanish Renaissance Architecture", 1927-1929, 1941-1942, undated (Box 43, Folder 13)
      - "Italian High Renaissance outside of Rome", 1931 (Box 43, Folder 14)
      - "Greek-Roman Architecture", 1927-1930 (Box 43, Folder 15)
      - "Greek and Roman Architecture", Undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
      - "Spanish-American Architecture", Undated (Box 43, Folder 17)
      - "Later Italian Renaissance", Undated (Box 43, Folder 18)
      - "French Renaissance Architecture", 1928 (Box 43, Folder 19)
      - "American Art and Architecture", 1937, undated (Box 43, Folder 20)
      - "English and Spanish Renaissance Architecture", Undated (Box 43, Folder 21)
      - "Three Centuries of Connecticut Architecture", 1937 (Box 43, Folder 22)
      - "Neo-Renaissance-Borrowed Styles", 1929, 1932, 1938 (Box 43, Folder 23)
      - "French Gothic Architecture", 1928, 1930, undated (Box 43, Folder 24)
      - "English and Italian Gothic Architecture", Undated (Box 43, Folder 25)
      - Portrait game, Undated (Box 43, Folder 26)
      - Class examinations-Yale School of Fine Arts, 1927-1946 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - "American Art and Architecture as an Expression of American Culture", 1937 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - "Byzantine and Italian Romanesque Architecture", 1929 (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - "Chicago Fair of 1893", 1940 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - "The Art of Paris and Its Survivors", Undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - "Romanesque Architecture", 1928-1930 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - "Colonial Architecture in the North", 1931 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - "Functionalism-Truth and Character in Architecture", 1929 (Box 44, Folder 8)
      - "Spanish Renaissance Architecture", Undated (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - "English Sources of American Architecture", 1931 (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - "The Classic Revival in American Architecture", 1932, undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - "Colonial and Republican Architecture", 1944 (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - "Residential Architecture", 1944-1947 (Box 44, Folder 13-14)
      - "Recreational Architecture", 1944-1947 (Box 44, Folder 15-16)
      - "Educational", 1927, 1941-1944, 1947 (Box 44, Folder 17-18)
      - "Recreation", 1942 (Box 44, Folder 19)
      - "Commercial and Exchange Architecture", 1942-1944 (Box 44, Folder 20)
      - "Government and Institutional Architecture", 1943-1945 (Box 44, Folder 21)
      - "Government and Institutional Architecture -Commemorative and Military", 1942-1945 (Box 44, Folder 22)
      - "Architecture Research-Religious", 1942-1943 (Box 44, Folder 23)
      - "Industrial Architecture", 1945 (Box 44, Folder 24)
      - "Religious Architecture", 1943-1945 (Box 44, Folder 25-26)
      - "City Planning", 1944-1947 (Box 44, Folder 27-29)
      - "Transportation Historical Research", 1942-1945 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - "Architectural Design-Old", 1920-1940 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - "Architectural Design-Recent", 1938-1941 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - "Classic and Mediaeval Architecture", 1937-1942 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - "Mediaeval Architecture", 1929-1940 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - "Renaissance and Modern Architecture", 1941-1942 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - "Renaissance and Modern Architecture", 1937-1939 (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - "Classic and Mediaeval Architecture", 1937-1938 (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - Clippings, 1930s (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - "Lecture on Rheims", Undated (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - "Old Italian Lesson", Undated (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - "Chinese Architecture", 1940 (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - "Perspectives", 1946 (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - "Tides in English Taste", Undated (Box 45, Folder 14)
- Notes, writings, and speeches, 1888-1956; Series VII
  - Architecture and travel
    - Canada, 1915 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - English and French cathedrals, 1902 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Europe, 1920-1926 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Mexico, 1930-1950 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - New York City architecture, Undated (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Rheims, France, Circa 1914-circa 1918 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Synopsis of travels, 1888-1956 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Travel plans, 1920-1940 (Box 46, Folder 9-10)
    - World War I restoration work in France, 1918 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      See also: Corresponding architectural drawings in Series IV, Drawings and sketches, Box 25, folder 3.
  - Personal
    - Family genealogy, Undated (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Housing options at Cornell University and New York City, Undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1895, undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Movies and books, 1897, 1950, undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Transcribed prayers, 1930-1950 (Box 47, Folder 5-6)
    - University Club at Columbia University, 1916 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Speeches, 1948, undated (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - By others
    - Ford, George--World War I devastation in France, American Red Cross, 1918 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1895-1921, undated (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Students, 1921, undated (Box 47, Folder 11)
- Official documents, 1856-1954; Series VIII
  - Educational
    Includes diplomas.
    - Cornell University, 1920 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - École des Beaux-Arts, 1904-1908 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Yale University, 1920-1930 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Personal
    - Indenture for land in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1856 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Insurance policies and will, 1918, 1934, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Leases, 1913-1916 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Marriage licenses, 1918, 1935 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Yale Navy training unit report, 1918 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Professional, 1908-1933 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    Includes architectural licenses.
  - Travel and passports
    - 1902-1927 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - 1910-1916 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - 1918-1919 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - 1933-1952 (Box 48, Folder 9)
- Photographs, 1873-1952, undated; Series IX
  The photographs are chiefly black-and-white prints with some hand-painted, tin types, negatives, and daguerreotypes mixed in.
  - Individuals
    - Family
      Additional family photographs of Charlotte Davenport, William Davenport, Sarah Elizabeth Shepherd, and others are located in Series XIII, Papers of Stevens's family members.
      - Boyd family, 1884-1889, undated
        - 1894-1889, undated (Box 50, Folder 1)
        - Daguerreotypes, Undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Charlotte Boyd (great grandmother)--daguerreotypes, Undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Charlotte Cordelia (Shepherd) Davenport--daguerreotypes, Undated (Box 51, Folder 3-4)
        See also: Photographs,Series XIII. Box 95-96, (p. 30).
      - Davenport family, 1883, undated
        - 1883, undated (Box 50, Folder 2)
        - Undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Emily (Bradley Quinn) Stevens (second wife), Circa 1940 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Nellie (Shepherd) Stevens (mother)--daguerreotypes (Box 51, Folder 5-6)
        See also: Photographs,Series XIII. Box 96, 101, 102.
      - Sarah Elizabeth (Boyd) Shepherd--daguerreotypes, Undated (Box 51, Folder 7-11)
        See also: Photographs,Series XIII. Box 101.
    - Miscellaneous portraits
      - Females
        - 1880-1940, undated (Box 53, Folder 1-6)
        - Undated (Box 63)
      - Groups
        - 1880-1940, undated (Box 50, Folder 5-7)
        - 1880-1940, undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - Males
        - 1880-1940, undated (Box 52, Folder 1-4)
        - Daguerreotypes, Undated (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Other individuals
      - William Beers and Thomas Ludlow (classmates), 1903, undated (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - Bayard Trumbull, Circa 1951 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Coffin family, 1910-1923, undated (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Shepherd Stevens
      - 1880-1889 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - 1889 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - 1899-1901 (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - 1904-1908 (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - 1908-1919 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - 1914-1916 (Box 55, Folder 6)
      - 1917-1919 (Box 55, Folder 7)
      - 1918 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - 1922-1952 (Box 55, Folder 9)
      - 1923-1928 (Box 55, Folder 10)
      - 1925-1926 (Box 55, Folder 11)
      - Undated (Box 55, Folder 12-13)
      - Undated (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Residences, Shepherd Stevens
    Residences contain detailed photographs of the interiors of Stevens's apartments and houses. Some of the interiors in France also include friends, family members, and classmates, in addition to displays of Stevens's architectural drawings.
    - Connecticut, 1926-1933, undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Interiors, Undated (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - New York
      - Brooklyn, Undated (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Ithaca, 1920, undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Manhattan, 1911 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Paris, 1904-1908 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Vermont, Undated (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Travel
    Many travel photographs include handwritten annotations identifying locations and subjects depicted.
    - Africa
      - Africa, Undated (Box 57, Folder 1-4)
      - Egypt, Undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
      - Tunisia, Undated (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Asia
      - Asia, 1932, undated (Box 57, Folder 7-12)
      - China, Undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - China and India, Undated (Box 58, Folder 2-4)
      - India, Undated (Box 58, Folder 5-12)
      - India, Undated (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
      - Japan, Undated (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - Japan and Korea, 1903, undated (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - Japan, China, India, Circa 1903 (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - Sri Lanka, Undated (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - Turkey, Undated (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Europe
      - England, 1908, undated (Box 59, Folder 8)
      - Europe, 1900, undated (Box 59, Folder 9-12)
      - France, 1910-1919, undated
        Includes École des Beaux-Arts, American Red Cross, and Rheims.
        - 1910 (Box 60, Folder 1)
        - 1912 (Box 60, Folder 2)
        - 1916 (Box 60, Folder 3-4)
        - 1918 (Box 60, Folder 5-9)
        - Undated (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Greece, Undated (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - Italy, 1930, undated (Box 60, Folder 12-13)
      - Switzerland, Undated (Box 60, Folder 14-15)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 60, Folder 16-18)
    - North America
      - Bermuda, Undated (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Canada, Undated (Box 61, Folder 2-3)
      - At sea, Undated (Box 61, Folder 4)
      - United States
        - Alaska, Undated (Box 61, Folder 5-6)
        - California, Undated (Box 61, Folder 7-10)
        - Massachusetts, Undated (Box 61, Folder 11)
        - New York, 1884, 1906, undated (Box 61, Folder 12)
        - Washington, District of Columbia, Undated (Box 61, Folder 13)
        - Western United States
          - 1913 (Box 62, Folder 1-2)
          - Undated (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Photograph albums
    Most albums are labeled with geographical locations and other information.
    - Portraits
      - Undated (Box 63)
      - Circa 1873-1889 (Box 64)
    - Africa, 1912 (Box 65)
    - Africa, Europe, and Ithaca residence, Undated (Box 66)
    - Around the world, 1903-1904 (Box 66)
    - Canada, 1915 (Box 65)
    - Europe, 1900 (Box 67)
    - Historic buildings, individuals, and landmarks, Undated (Box 68)
    - New York City and Paris, Circa 1900 (Box 69)
    - Trip to Europe, 1889 (Box 70)
      This album includes photographs of St. John the Divine in New York City before its completion and the house of Elbridge T. Gerry.
    - United States and Canada, 1898 (Box 71)
    - Western United States, 1913 (Box 65)
- Postcards-blank, Undated; Series X
  - Europe, Asia, mountain ranges, and others (Box 72, Folder 1-20)
  - United States, Europe, Asia, and others (Box 73, Folder 1-17)
- Printed material, 1789-1961; Series XI
  - Booklets and pamphlets
    - Apartment guides, Undated (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Exhibitions, 1938, 1960-1961 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Furniture, 1956, undated (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Historic structures, 1913,1924,1930,1960 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1900-1940 (Box 74, Folder 5-8)
    - Travel, 1894-1951 (Box 74, Folder 9-14)
  - Clippings
    - Architecture and planning, 1920-1955 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Books, arts, and culture, 1897-1920 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1920-1952 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Obituaries, 1880-1959 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Political, 1910-1950 (Box 75, Folder 5-8)
    - Stevens, Shepherd, 1917-1925, undated (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Topics of the time, 1930-1950 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Travel, 1890-1955 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Yale University, 1925, 1929, undated (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - Dining menus, 1886-1914 (Box 74, Folder 15)
  - Invitations
    - Art and architectural events, 1904-1920 (Box 76, Folder 1)
      Includes events at the École des Beaux-Arts and Yale University School of Fine Arts.
    - Balls, memorials, dinners, 1904-1908, 1930 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Weddings
      - 1879, 1902-1920 (Box 76, Folder 3)
      - Undated (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Maps, 1900-1940 (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - Visiting cards
    - Blank, Undated (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - Others, Undated (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - Stevens, Shepherd, Undated (Box 74, Folder 19)
  - Posters, maps, prints
    - 1900-1920, Undated (Folder 77)
    - Fuertes, Louis Agassiz, 1906 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - World War I announcement taken from municipal theater in Rheims, France, 1918 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Wall calendars, 1895 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Programs and printed memorabilia
    - American Shakespeare Festival Theater and Academy, 1959 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Carols, 1900-1950 (Box 74, Folder 20-23)
    - Libretto, 1900-1905 (Box 79, Folder 1-3)
    - Music scores
      - 1860-1940 (Box 80, Folder 1-5)
      - 1860-1940 (Box 81, Folder 1-4)
      - William Vincent Wallace album, Undated (Box 82)
      - Mendelssohn album, 1883-1884 (Box 82)
    - Playbills, 1890-1950 (Box 79, Folder 4-12)
    - Programs, 1900-1940 (Box 79, Folder 13-14)
    - Souvenir books, 1899-1901 (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - Theater records and scrapbook albums, 1890-1950 (Box 86)
    - Yale University Library, Undated (Box 79, Folder 16)
  - Publications
    - Architecture publications
      - 1905, 1940 (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 1910-1920 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Art gallery and museum publications, 1908-1948 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - College entrance examination board publication, 1953, 1957 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Gray's Elegy, 1903 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Magazines and newspapers
      - Brooklyn Daily Eagle and Brooklyn Life, 1904, 1917 (Box 83, Folder 3)
      - Daily Mail, 1918 (Box 83, Folder 4)
      - Federal Gazette and Philadelphia Evening Post, 1789 (Box 83, Folder 5)
      - Old-Time New England
        - 1957-1958 (Box 83, Folder 6)
        - 1959-1961 (Box 83, Folder 7)
      - Harper's Ferry, 1850-1950 (Box 83, Folder 8)
      - La Baïonnette, 1916-1917 (Box 83, Folder 9)
      - Mindener Nachrichten, 1918 (Box 83, Folder 10)
        A German newspaper (dated December 12, 1918) found in a house after World War I by the homeowner.
      - Red Cross Bulletin, 1918 (Box 83, Folder 11)
      - The Illustrated London News, 1937 (Box 83, Folder 12)
      - The Theater, 1901 (Box 83, Folder 13)
      - Travel related, 1913, 1915 (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Material on Authur Kingsley Porter, 1933-1934 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Material on wood engraver Alexander Drake, 1913, 1927 (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - University publications
      - Columbia University, 1903, 1916-1917 (Box 84, Folder 5)
      - Cornell University, 1916-1917 (Box 84, Folder 6)
      - École des Beaux-Arts, 1917 (Box 84, Folder 7)
      - Yale University
        - 1919-1923 (Box 84, Folder 8)
        - 1920-1950 (Box 84, Folder 9)
        - 1926-1934 (Box 84, Folder 10)
        - 1927-1957 (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - War related, 1913-1920 (Box 84, Folder 12-13)
    - The Runner's Bible, 1913 (Box 84, Folder 14)
    - The Book of Common Prayer, 1840 (Box 84, Folder 15)
    - The Famous Collections Formed by Mr. A.W. Drake, 1913 (Box 84, Folder 16)
  - Travel images, Undated (Box 85, Folder 1-16)
- Miscellanea, 1818-1955; Series XII
  - Address books and directories
    - 1909-1910 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - 1918 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Undated (Box 88, Folder 3-4)
  - Autograph book, 1889-1909 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Book plates, 1908-1910, undated (Box 87)
    The book plates include those of Shepherd Stevens and others.
  - Currency, 1818-1945 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Dinner party books
    - 1931-1939 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - 1939-1944 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Fabric samples, Undated (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Personal objects, Undated (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - Stamps
    - Food ration, 1918 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Postage, 1880-1950 (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - Visitor's book
    - 1919-1929 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - 1922-1943 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - 1942-1955 (Box 89, Folder 3)
- Papers of Stevens's family members, 1822-1931; Series XIII
  This series is arranged according to the significance of the family member, with those closest to Shepherd Stevens listed first. The papers for each family focus on personal and professional activities, and travels.
  - Charlotte Cordelia (Shepherd) Davenport (aunt)
    - Correspondence
      - 1861-1912 (Box 90, Folder 1-27)
      - 1913-1929, undated (Box 91, Folder 1-8)
    - Diaries
      - 1865-1892 (Box 91, Folder 9-20)
      - 1893-1907 (Box 92, Folder 1-15)
      - 1908-1920 (Box 93, Folder 1-13)
      - 1921-1931 (Box 94, Folder 1-11)
    - Financial records, 1930 (Box 94, Folder 12)
    - Official documents, 1870, 1917, undated (Box 94, Folder 13)
    - Photographs
      See also: Daguerreotypes, Box 51.
      - 1890-1919, undated (Box 95, Folder 1-9)
      - 1902, 1912 (Box 96, Folder 1)
      - Photograph album - Lake Lucerne and Geneva, 1888 (Box 95, Folder 10)
    - Writings and memorabilia
      - Personal items
        - 1918, 1927 (Box 94, Folder 14)
        - Pressed flower album, 1885 (Box 97)
      - Writings
        - Autograph album and poem book, 1865 (Box 94, Folder 15)
        - Individual poems
          - 1890-1919, undated (Box 95, Folder 11)
          - 1920-1929, undated (Box 95, Folder 12-13)
          - 1930, undated (Box 95, Folder 14-16)
        - Poem books
          - 1913 (Box 95, Folder 17)
          - Undated (Box 95, Folder 18)
        - Travel notes
          - "A Westward Journey", 1895 (Box 94, Folder 16)
          - Europe, Undated (Box 94, Folder 17)
  - William Bates Davenport (uncle)
    - Biographical sketch of William Davenport, Undated (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Clippings on William Davenport, 1880-1929 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1873-1929 (Box 98, Folder 3-19)
    - Diaries
      - 1908-1915 (Box 98, Folder 20-23)
      - 1921-1925 (Box 99, Folder 1-3)
    - Financial records, 1893, 1910, 1927 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Official documents
      - Certificate from the General Society of Colonial Wars, 1919 (Box 96, Folder 3)
      - Passports and Congressional passes, 1873-1921 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Photographs
      - 1890-1910, undated (Box 99, Folder 5-6)
      - Undated (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Sarah Elizabeth (Boyd) Shepherd (grandmother)
    - Correspondence, 1837-1865 (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - Diaries
      - 1842-1896 (Box 99, Folder 8-20)
      - 1897-1898 (Box 101, Folder 1-2)
    - Drawings and sketchbooks
      - Individual drawings, 1840-1860 (Box 101, Folder 3-4)
      - Sketchbooks, Circa 1830-circa 1850 (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - Photographs
      - 1894, undated (Box 101, Folder 6)
      - 1897-1898 (Box 101, Folder 7)
      - Undated (Box 101, Folder 8)
    - Samplers, 1836, 1840 (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - Writings
      - Autograph and poem book, 1839 (Box 101, Folder 10)
      - Biographical sketch of Boyd family, 1876 (Box 101, Folder 11)
      - Individual notes and poems, 1839-1845, undated (Box 101, Folder 12)
      - Poem books, 1834, 1840 (Box 101, Folder 13)
  - Mary (Wilder Breckenridge) Stevens (first wife)
    - Correspondence, 1918-1925 (Box 101, Folder 14-16)
    - Photographs
      - 1922-1924, undated (Box 101, Folder 17-18)
      - Undated (Box 96, Folder 5)
      - Children
        - Anne Breckenridge (daughter), 1922, undated (Box 101, Folder 19)
        - James Breckenridge (son), 1918-1922, undated (Box 101, Folder 20)
  - Charlotte Boyd (great-grandmother)
    - Correspondence, 1849-1870 (Box 101, Folder 21)
    - Financial records, 1835-1870 (Box 101, Folder 22)
  - Nellie (Shepherd) Stevens (mother)
    - Marriage license to Thomas Henry Stevens, 1878 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Photographs
      - 1875, undated (Box 101, Folder 23)
      - Undated (Box 96, Folder 7)
      - Photograph album--portraits, 1876 (Box 102)
  - Thomas Henry Stevens (father)
    - Address book, 1878 (Box 101, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1869, 1903, undated (Box 101, Folder 25)
    - Photographs, 1873-1889, undated (Box 101, Folder 26)
  - William Stokes Boyd (great-uncle)
    - Correspondence, 1850-1857 (Box 101, Folder 27)
      Includes an account of laying the first transatlantic cable from the U.S.S. Niagara